hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
and today we are going to talk about
another interesting topic in class
centers Tosca
so today I'm going to discuss about how
you can add different desktop libraries
and then how you can basically add
different reusable tester blocks inside
this libraries which can be used or
reused across different test cases
now what is the need for this
so in any test automation framework you
always have different common uh reusable
libraries right this increases the
reusability factor which is very
important for any framework and also it
becomes easy for us to maintain our test
cases because I will be using this
reusable libraries which can be then
changed at only one place rather than
changing it everywhere right so it saves
time
it makes our development move faster
right and more efficient
so in other Frameworks uh you might have
to do some customization or you have to
build these reusable libraries right but
uh in Tosca it already provides your
future where you can create this desktop
libraries and if you have already
created your test cases you can just uh
convert this the steps into reusable
tester blocks which will then be part of
the library
and then these blocks can be used as a
reference in different test cases right
so this is the flow how a Tosca follows
or how Tosca uses the desktop libraries
right it is part of the test cases
section right so you can create this
desktop libraries anywhere
and these libraries could be reused
across different test cases okay
so to demonstrate this particular
feature I have created a folder called
reusable libraries I have two test cases
they are pretty similar uh with very
limited functionality just to show you
how this works so one is login with the
valid user one is login with invalid
user there are just two steps open URL
and login user the first one is using a
valid user and the second one is using a
invalid user okay now if I run them you
will see there is not much difference
obviously I could have added lot more
steps after this two steps okay but
these are the two steps uh which I feel
are common for my application okay and
that is the reason
um I have I'm going to use them as
reusable desktop blocks okay
so you can see in the first test case uh
it logged in with a valid user into the
website and then you can continue from
there but in case of this invalid user
it will give this message and we can
also verify this and then we can
continue
moving forward with um whatever test
case scenario we have okay
so these are the two examples where you
see there are common steps right so the
common steps are opening the URL and
logging in with a user
so even though that this step data is
different right so one is valid one is
invalid but still this can be handled in
just one common reusable steps so this
makes a good case for using a library
instead of having the same steps with
different test data and two different
test cases okay
so um how we can create them uh we can
create them inside the same folder okay
so right click on this and then you will
see a folder uh with a l sign and that's
what is a test step Library okay
so you can also use the shortcut control
and control L to create this so click on
this and this will create a library here
okay
and inside this library now I can create
a usable desktop block okay
or I can also if I have already created
my test cases and I have the test steps
okay I can also uh convert this into my
reusable tester blocks okay
so how you can do that is I can just
drag it here okay and I can
drag this to basically uh steps and make
it a reusable tester blocks okay so you
can see here now this has become a
reusable stress the block
and in the test case it has now changed
uh into a arrow sign so which means it
is just a reference okay so it is not
the actual step it is a reference to
this particular steps
okay and uh now how I can reuse these
steps so these reusables test the blocks
I can basically delete these steps in my
second test case
and now I can just drag this reusable
desktop blocks into my test case okay so
you can see uh these are almost the same
reusable desktop blocks okay but they
are not different they are references to
the same uh tester blocks and this you
can do it across all your test cases so
wherever your test cases are using these
two uh steps which is opening the URL
and logging in the user you can use it
uh anywhere okay any test case you can
just pull this references into a test
cases and they will run them
okay so that solves one of our problem
uh where we are now using two common
steps which are part of a library
but now you can think uh these values
right these values are still the same
so uh it will basically do the same
thing right now it will login with the
same user which is present in this
library right but I want it to be more
customized so that I can use my own
values right I can use the own
um invalid user in the second test case
rather than a valid user so that my
scenario is as per the expectations okay
so for that uh you need to now uh
convert okay this or you need to add
business parameters
so whatever values you want to
parameterize like the username the
password or the URL okay which can
change across different test cases
you can basically add business
parameters for these okay
and to do this uh you need to click on
the usable tester block
and there is an option to create
business parameter container okay
so we can add that and we can create our
business parameters here
right
once you do that now I can add different
parameters here
as you can see so first parameter would
be username
and the second parameter would be
password so these are the two values
which can be parameterized okay in this
particular tester block
and then in url also I can parameterize
the URL path so I will do that
so I'll create a business parameter for
URL okay
you don't need to provide any values or
action mode or data type for this
business parameters they are just
parameters okay
and what we need to do is now we need to
delete these values okay
because we'll not be using this values
which are static in nature right we'll
be using these parameters instead of any
particular value
so you have to replace them with these
parameters okay
let me drag this again
so now once you drag these parameters
into this the steps right so it will
become a PL and Then followed by that
parameter name so PL means the business
parameter
so similarly for open URL
I will remove this value and I will drag
this URL parameter here
okay
so now you can see that our usable
tester blocks are actually reusable
right because they are not using any
static values it can be used across any
test case so any particular login test
case where it has got these fields and
you can enter any value from the test
case itself okay
so um now our library and usable tester
blocks are ready now if I go back to my
test case right you will see that the
business parameters are already created
okay
and you will see all the test step
values have now been removed from this
references you just need to pass a valid
URL a username and password
now you can again configure it more you
can put a configuration parameter in
your folder and you can use that here
rather than putting the directly rather
than putting the URL directly here right
same you can do with username or
password
but now you can see that uh even though
I use it in two different test cases I
can enter different values based on my
test cases Okay so
it is now actually uh using some
reusable steps uh which can have their
own values in different test cases okay
so for this particular example
um let's go to this URL and let's try to
put different values here okay so just
to complete these two scenarios
so these are the username and password
which I'm going to use so first one is
the valid user
okay
so that's my first test case and in the
second one I am going to use this logged
out user so that it throws an error
message
okay and then the URL
so a URL is as you can see it is same
and as I said you don't need to enter it
directly here you can create a
configuration parameter like we have
done many times okay so create a test
configuration parameter for URL and just
use that here
okay but as you can see now we have got
two test cases using uh usable tester
blocks from a library but having
different values using the business
parameters okay
and now if I run them they should still
run as expected like we have seen before
there should be no difference
okay so that's our first test case
and if I now run my second test case
okay so it should display this error
message which can be verified of course
but uh okay so that's that's the results
we have got okay so we haven't put any
verifications but the purpose of this
particular demo was to show you how you
can use a library and the reusable
tester blocks with business parameters
so a very useful way of reusing your
test steps across your test cases
okay so this could be used in many
complex uh scenarios where you have got
test cases with a number of different
test steps so find out which are the
common ones and put it as reusable
desktop blocks in your libraries
so that's all for this session but do
tune in into our Channel if you have not
subscribed do subscribe so that you get
a notification whenever I come up with
more interesting scenarios or
interesting features available in class
centers.com